<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>io.github.anechunaev.notion-electron</id>
  <name>Notion Electron</name>
  <summary>Unofficial Notion client (including Calendar and Mail)</summary>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.anechunaev.notion-electron.desktop</launchable>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>Unofficial desktop application for Notion, built as an Electron wrapper with additional features.</p>
    <p>Some of notable features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><em>Integrated Notion Tools</em> — Fully functional dedicated tabs for Notion Calendar and Notion Mail within the same application. This approach saves system memory by reusing a single Electron process compared to running separate clients.</li>
      <li><em>Theme Support</em> — Switch effortlessly between light and dark UI themes.</li>
      <li><em>Tray Icon</em> — Minimize the application to the system tray for quick access. For environments without the tray like Gnome, there are actions available to access options and updates.</li>
      <li><em>Performance Tweaks</em> — Optimized to reduce startup time for faster access.</li>
      <li><em>Browser-Like Tabs</em> — Tabs behave just like in a web browser: each has its own history, can be reordered, pinned, or even dragged from Notion Electron to your browser.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/anechunaev/notion-electron/issues</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://anechunaev.github.io/notion-electron</url>
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </recommends>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/anechunaev/notion-electron/refs/heads/main/docs/screenshot_notes.png</image>
      <caption>Default view of Notion Electron</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/anechunaev/notion-electron/refs/heads/main/docs/screenshot_calendar.png</image>
      <caption>Notion Calendar</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.9.2" date="2025-11-17">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed visual bug when Chromium window do not respect system-wide color scheme (issue #1)</li>
          <li>Fixed bug when multiple tabs would not re-open on application start (issue #44)</li>
          <li>Fixed application icon not applying in some desktop environments</li>
          <li>Added D-Bus integration to call actions (Options, Updates, About) for inter-process communications</li>
          <li>Added actions (Options, Updates, About) in Activities screen for Gnome desktop environment</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <developer_name>Artem Nechunaev</developer_name>
  <update_contact>artem_at_nechunaev.com</update_contact>
</component>